♪〜
〜♪
A $ $700,000 reward for the
escaped convicts, the Nebraska Family!
（助手）脱走犯 ネブラスカ親子に
70万ダブドルの賞金か
That's huge!
すっげーなあ
Hold it! Take that down.
（保安官）ちょっと待った
それ 剥がしてくれ
（助手）えっ なぜです？
- Why?
- They were caught.
（保安官）捕まったからだよ
えっ？ 手配から５時間しか
たってないじゃないですか
It's only been 5 hours
since the warrant was issued!
That's a new speed record!
スピード記録だ
You'll be more surprised
when you see who caught them.
ハンターの欄を見れば
もっと驚くぞ
“アイプリル市民一同”？
"The entire city of Inepril"?!
What is this?!
何です？ これ
Just like it says.
The entire city probably jumped 'em.
書いてあるとおりさ
町ぐるみで倒したんだろ
That's a lot of divvying.
賞金は山分けか
Maybe it's populated
by a bunch of macho men.
マッチョの集団でも
住んでるのかな？
（ヴァッシュ･ザ･スタンピード）
モグモグ…
Are you really sure about this?
（会長）ホントにいいのかね
わしら あんたを狙ってたんだぞ
We tried to kill you.
And you're the one who
defeated the Nebraska Family.
（ヘンリー）
それに ネブラスカ親子を
倒したのは あんただ
So why did you
pass up the $ $700,000?
なのに どうして
70万ダブドルの権利を…
Well, why not?
まあ いいじゃない
モグモグ…
どうせ西へ東への根無し草稼業
A pile of money like that would just
be a nuisance to a drifter like me.
大金は邪魔なだけだし
And besides, now I can eat all
the salmon sandwiches I want here!
それに ここのサーモンサンドが
無制限で食えるようになったんだ
Right, Grams?
なあ おばちゃん
Darn tootin'! Eat up!
ああ たんと食べな
I'm jealous.
（ミリィ･トンプソン）
うらやましい
He could have bought up
every sandwich factory with that.
（メリル･ストライフ）
サンドイッチ工場
全部 買える額よ
あう…
（メリル）
さて… お話は終わりまして？
Well then,
have you finished your talk?
（会長）あ… まあ
Well, yes...
Then you had better
get away from him.
なら早く離れたほうが
いいですわよ
After all, this man is...
なんてったって この人は—
...Vash the Stampede, you know!
ヴァッシュ･ザ･スタンピード
なんですから
Isn't that right?
そうですわね？
まっ まあね
Well, yeah...
フンッ どうしてこんな人が…
Why did it have to be him?
Make way, make way!
はいはい
皆さん どいてください
Vash the Stampede is coming through!
ヴァッシュ･ザ･スタンピードが
通りますわよ
He's wanted for $ $60,000,000,000,
feared as The Humanoid Typhoon...
600億ダブドルの賞金首で—
ヒューマノイド･タイフーンと
恐れられている—
伝説のすご腕ガンマンですわよ
...he's the legendary
ace gunman, folks!
近づいて かまれても
保険金なんか下りませんわよ
If you go near him and he bites you,
don't expect any medical coverage!
よう ヴァッシュさん
あとで酒場に来てくれよ
Hey, Mr. Vash!
Stop by the saloon later.
We got some of the good stuff!
いいのが手に入ったんだ
（ヴァッシュ）ハハハハ…
（メリル）ガルルル
（ヴァッシュ）うーん…
Hi, Vash!
はーい！ ヴァッシュ
（ヴァッシュ）イヒヒヒヒ…
（メリル）ガルルル
（ヴァッシュ）い？ うーん…
ねえ いつまでこんなこと
するつもりなの？ 君たち
Hey, how long are you guys
gonna hang around me like this?
Always!
ずっとですよ
ヴァッシュさんの関わる事件の
被害を抑制するのが—
It's our job to control the damages
in cases which involve you.
私たちの仕事なんですから
Right, ma'am?
ねっ 先輩
That's right.
（メリル）そうですわね
（ヴァッシュ）えーっ！
That's the face
I want to make!
そういう顔をしたいのは
私ですのよ
あなたのせいで—
Do you have any idea how much money
the society lost because of you?!
協会の資金が どれだけ
飛んでいったと思ってますの？
（ミリィ）まあまあ 先輩
Now, now, ma'am...
I've found you,
Vash the Stampede!!
（トニス）見つけたぜ
ヴァッシュ･ザ･スタンピード
It's a bounty hunter!!
賞金稼ぎだ！
（おもちゃの銃の音）
（メリルとミリィ）うう…
Nice try!
（ヴァッシュ）まだまだだな
Nuts! I thought we'd get you!
（トニス）チェッ
ウマくいくと思ったのに
Lucky for me,
these girls aren't on the ball!
このお姉ちゃんたちが
のんびり屋さんで助かったよ
ハハハ…
（メリル）
アハハハ… アハッ アハハ
（ミリィ）チョー 分かります 先輩
でも ここは抑えてー！
I understand how you feel, ma'am,
but please calm yourself!!
（ごう音）
（２人）あっ？
It's the sand steamer!
（トニス）サンドスチームだ
（汽笛）
（男性Ａ）よっしゃ 商売 商売！
（男性Ｂ）急げー！
- Time to open shop!
- Hurry!!
It's a Humpback Class.
ハンプバッククラスですわ
私 こんな
大きなサンドスチーム見たの—
I've never seen such
a huge sand steamer!
初めてです
（男性Ｃ）行くぜ
It's incredible...
（ミリィ）すごいですね
（メリル）ええ
Yes...
Milly, where's Vash?
ミリィ　ヴァッシュさんは？
あっ… いません
He's gone.
What shall we do?
どうしますの？
What should we do?
どうしましょう？
（町のにぎわい）
Look at this!
It's the latest tasselled bugle!
（男性Ａ）見ろよ
ターセルの新型ビーグルだ
Holy moly!
（男性Ｂ）すっげー
How about this much?
（商人）こんなもんで どうだい？
Come on, I've got
kids to feed!
（客）おいおい
そりゃ足元 見過ぎだぜ
Hey, do you need
an extra hard worker?
（カイト）なあ とっても働き者(もん)の
人手はいらないかい？
I could use a hard worker,
but not a kid.
人手は欲しいが
ガキはごめんだ
（カイト）チェッ
It's like an annual festival.
まさに年に１度のお祭りじゃな
The timing couldn't be better!
いいタイミングでしたよ
The plant engineers
came on the steamer...
船には連絡しておいた
プラント技師が乗ってるし—
...and we have more
than enough to pay them.
資金も十分にある
My idea of calling in the
Nebraska Family saved the day.
ネブラスカ親子を呼んだ
わしのアイデアの勝利じゃな
一歩間違えてたら大惨事でしたよ
One false move would
have spelled disaster.
You're no fun.
すまんね
（人々のどよめき）
There's a real looker
on that ship!
（男性）
すげえ ねえちゃんが来たぞ
（女性）まあ キレイな人
What a beautiful lady!
（運転手）エヘヘヘ
（衝突音）
（運転手）ああっ
Hey, girl,
wanna go out with me?
（ソドム）よう ねえちゃん
俺とつきあわねえか？
I'm Sodum, the guy
in charge of this city.
俺はこの町を仕切ってる
ソドムってんだ
Hey, don't be so cold!
おいおい つれねえじゃねえかよ
おっと…
（倒れる音）
Watch where you're going, dolt!
どこ見てやがる トンチキ野郎！
Don't you know that
I'm Supersonic Sodum?!
この俺様が
音速のソドムだと知って…
えっ
知らないほうが
私の身のためです
It's better for me
if you don't know.
D-Don't tell me...
まっ まさか…
アハハハ…
You were just tired.
（ヴァッシュ）疲れてたんだな
（足音）
（ヴァッシュ）うん？
Vash the Stampede...
（エリザベス）
ヴァッシュ･ザ･スタンピード
Age unknown, origin unknown,
no fixed address.
年齢不明 出身地不明 住所不定
Wanted for the murder of
Count Lebnant Vasques...
レブナントヴァスケス伯爵殺害—
...and the suspicion of
class-G property damage.
および
Ｇ級器物破損容疑で指名手配中
They will pay $ $60,000,000,000
for you, dead or alive.
賞金金額は生死に関わらず
600億ダブドル
わあっ！
（エリザベス）フフッ
I know all about you.
私 あなたのことなら
何でも知っているのよ
それなら話は早い
今すぐ結婚しましょう…
That makes it so much quicker!
Let's get married right now!!
Wonderful proposal.
ステキな申し出ね
でしょ？ でしょ？
Ain't it, though?
But I have you
at a disadvantage.
でも不公平だわ
You don't know
anything about me.
だって あなたは
私のことを知らないんだもの
フッ 聞かなくても分かりますよ
I can tell all on my own.
You are a passerby
who had her heart stolen...
平和を愛する孤高のガンマンに
心を奪われた行きずりの女
...by a peace-loving gunman
who stands alone.
In a word, a fairy princess.
ひと言で言うと… 妖精？
My name is Elizabeth.
（エリザベス）私はエリザベス
I'm the chief engineer
of the Marius Bresken Kantacle...
メリウス･ビレスキーヌ･カンタクル
技術工業組合の—
...Technical Industrial Union
work dispatch team.
派遣作業チームの主任よ
In short, you're a fairylike
plant engineer?
つまり妖精のような
プラント技師ですね
Do you know anything about plants?
あなた プラントについてご存じ？
へっ？ 100年以上前の
ロストテクノロジーでしたっけ？
Aren't they, like, lost technology
from over a hundred years ago?
That's right.
（エリザベス）そうよ
They are systems which can achieve
production beyond all theoretical law.
理論法則を超えた
生産活動を行うシステム
They are the leftovers from the
Pandora's Box we were given by God...
この劣悪な環境で
私たちが生きていくために—
神が与えたパンドラの箱に
残っていたもの
...that allow you and I
to exist in this poor environment.
I came here to keep
that hope alive.
その希望をつなぎとめるために
私はここに来たのよ
And our marriage?
…で 結婚は？
First, I want you
to do a job for me.
その前に１つ仕事を頼みたいの
Is there a reward in it?
報酬とかあります？
I'll give you what you want.
あなたの望むものをあげるわ
望むもんが…
What I want?
I'll do it, I'll do it!
I'll do whatever you want!!
やります やります 何でもやります
（市場のにぎわい）
はーい 安いよ 安いよ
Over here!
Everything's dirt cheap!
Here's a piping hot one.
ほれ アツアツを食いな
Ooh, thanks!
（子どもたちのはしゃぐ声）
For crying out loud,
where did that man go?!
まったく あの男は
どこ行ったんですの？
All of these extra people
make it extra hard to find him.
ドバッと人が増えて
捜すのも苦労しますね
That doesn't mean
he's in there.
だからって
そんなとこにはいませんわよ
（男）おう！ カワイイじゃん 彼女
Hey there, cutie!
I'm ready and willing to be
your obedient little doggie!
今の僕なら
君に従順な愛玩動物になれるよ
But you're just a child.
子どもが何 言ってますの？
That's right! She may not
look it, but she's twenty...
（ミリィ）そうですよ
先輩はこれでも にじゅう…
He doesn't need to know that!
よけいなこと言わない！
Yeah, I'd advise against it!
She's really uptight!
（ヴァッシュ）そうそう
やめといたほうがいいよ
彼女 チョー きついから
Excuse me?!
なんですって！
Mr. Vash!
（ミリィ）ヴァッシュさん
What? Vash?!
えっ ヴァッシュ？ ひゃー！
Where have you b...
あなた どこに行って… あっ
Who is that?
どなたですの？
A total babe!
（ヴァッシュ）すっごい美人
That's not what I mean.
いや そうでなくって…
I asked him to protect me while
I revise the plant system program.
（エリザベス）
プラントのシステムプログラムを
修正しているあいだの—
護衛を頼んだんですのよ
（ミリィとメリル）はあ…
Oh.
Come, Spot!
（エリザベス）おいで ポチ
（ヴァッシュ）ワン！
（ミリィとメリル）えっ ポチ？
SPOT?
- Where's the hotel?
- We're almost there, master!
（エリザベス）ホテルはどこ？
もうすぐです ご主人様
Thank you, Spot.
（エリザベス）ありがとう ポチ
（ヴァッシュ）ワン！
It's good we found him,
isn't it, ma'am?
見つかってよかったですね 先輩
Aren't we going to follow him?
追わないんですか？
I'd rather do paperwork
than keep watch over that idiot!
（メリル）あんな男の監視より
書類整理やってたほうがマシですわ
（エリザベス）明日の早朝６時に
修復作業を始めるから—
I'm beginning the restoration work
at 6am sharp, so don't be late.
そのつもりで
Don't worry! I've been called
Rooster Boy, Early Bird, et cetera.
（ヴァッシュ）大丈夫です
“ニワトリ起こし”
“日曜日の子ども”などなどの—
異名を持ってますから
（ドアが閉まる音）
（ヴァッシュ）ああ…
一緒の部屋じゃないの？
Aren't we in the same room?
Not until my work is done, Spot.
You sleep in the innermost room.
（エリザベス）
お仕事が済んでからね ポチ
あなたは一番奥の部屋よ
Good night.
おやすみ
（ヴァッシュ）ああ…
思うようにはいかないねえ
It never goes my way.
来る
Something's coming.
（窓が割れる音）
（ヴァッシュ）うわっ はっ
うわっ ひきょうだぞ 君
Hey, you're not playing fair!
ううっ
あっ… おおっ
（銃声）
Oopsies.
おっと… 俺は
男と寝る趣味はないんだよね
I don't like sleeping with men.
Would you go now?
黙って消えてくんない？
Gee, he did as I asked.
えっ 意外と素直に…
ん？
（時限爆弾の音）
（爆発音）
ハアッ ハアッ
うん？
な… 何だ？ こりゃ ひでえ
What? This is horrible!
Oh, hey! Pay it no mind
and go back to sleep!
（ヴァッシュ）ああ
気にせずにお休みください
It's V-V-V-Vash!!!
うわっ ヴァ… ヴァッシュだ
うわーっ
I'm glad I switched our room
numbers in the hotel registry!
（エリザベス）
宿帳のルームナンバーを
反対に書いといてよかったわ
That's not fair!
それ ずるい
Aren't you protecting me?
（エリザベス）
護衛してくれるんでしょ？
I'd at least like an explanation.
せめて理由ぐらいは聞きたいな
Tomorrow.
あしたね
I lost my room,
so can I share yours?
（ヴァッシュ）
部屋なくなっちゃったから
そっちに行っていい？
But you have
a bed right there.
そこにベッドがあるじゃない
（風の音）
So cold...
寒い…
I sure am glad you
Bernardelli people are here.
（ホテルのオーナー）
ベルナルデリの人がいてくれて
助かったよ
ほれ 保険加入証明書だ
Here's my insurance policy.
By the way, who was
staying in this room?
（メリル）ところで
部屋に泊まっていた客は—
どなたでしたの？
Can't you tell by looking?
このありさまで分かるだろう
ヴァッシュ･ザ･スタンピードだよ
It was Vash the Stampede.
あ… あの男
That guy...
There is only one reason
why anyone would be after me.
（エリザベス）
私が狙われている理由は
１つしかないわ
Plant control uses much
of the lost technology...
プラントの制御は—
ロストテクノロジーを
いくつも使うし—
その知識を私は持っている
...and the knowledge
to use it is in my head.
Still, that doesn't mean I
understand what the plant really is.
…と言っても—
プラントそのものを
把握しているわけではないけどね
How have you managed so far?
今まで どうしてたんですか？
The union always
sent an escort with me.
組合が常時
ガードを同行させてくれていたわ
But when I came here
you were here for me.
でも この町には
あなたがいるじゃない
I'll strive to live
up to your expectations!
ご期待に沿えるよう頑張ります
Hey, you!
You can't come in here!
（作業員Ａ）おい コラッ
勝手に入ってはいかん
We're working!
（作業員Ｂ）作業中だぞ
I hear that you're behind
the hotel explosion.
ホテルの爆発事故の原因は
あなただそうですわね
Y-You got the wrong idea!
ご… 誤解だ
（メリル）あなたのせいですわね
It was your fault, wasn't it?!
The chief will get mad at us
for not doing our job!
仕事しなかったって
部長に怒られちゃいます〜
But I was the victim!
被害者はこっちだって
それに あんた それ
ウソ泣きでしょ？
Besides, you're
not really crying.
At any rate, you cannot be allowed
into an important place like this!
とにかく こんな大事な場所に—
あなたをいさせるわけには
いきませんわ
But I need him here.
それは困るわね
Spot is guarding me, after all.
ポチは私のガードをしてるんだから
He may look harmless,
but he is still Vash the Stampede.
この男はこんな顔してても—
ヴァッシュ･ザ･スタンピード
ですのよ
That's why I came to him.
だから頼んだのよ
I'm telling you that trouble
swarms in this man's footsteps!
この男は歩くだけで—
トラブルが なだれを起こす
人間だと言ってるんです
Chief!
（作業員Ｃ）主任
第３区画で異常が発生しました
There's a malfunction
in section no.3!
What timing!
タイミング ドンピシャ
ノー！
Nooo!
The production system in plant no.4
suddenly started operating!
第４プラントの生産システムが
突然稼働しました
Shut down the main!
メインをダウンさせて
（作業員Ｃ）はっ
Yes, ma'am!
It's no good.
It's not shutting down!
ダメです　止まりません
This is bad. We'll have to
send the plant new data directly.
やっかいね
プラントに直接データを送って
書き換えないと
- Spot?
- Yes?
（エリザベス）ポチ
（ヴァッシュ）はい！
- Come with me.
- Coming!
（エリザベス）一緒に来て
（ヴァッシュ）はい！
あっ ちょっと待って！
Wait a minute!
Please understand.
Even if I must shake you free...
分かってくれ
君を振り払っても
俺は行かなくちゃいけないんだ
...I must go!
The situation is
dynamically wrong here!
シチュエーションが
ダイナミックに間違ってますわよ
先輩 避難しましょう
Ma'am, let's take shelter!
Trouble is already swarming after him!
もう トラブルが
なだれを起こしています
ハア ハア
ハア ハア ハア ハア…
- Flip the switch.
- Right!
（エリザベス）スイッチ入れて
（ヴァッシュ）はい
- Get in.
- Right!
（エリザベス）入って
（ヴァッシュ）はい
あっ 下がって！
Get back!
（ケスカス）ハハハ…
Run.
逃げて
（エリザベス）ああ…
Can't you run?
ダメっすか？
Finished warming up?
準備運動は終わったかい？
（ヴァッシュ）ふん！
（ケスカス）うわあっ
（銃声）
（ケスカス）ああ…
（ケスカス）あっ ああ…
どうして君が こんな所にいるのか
摩訶(まか)不思議
It's a mystery to me
how you got in here.
（銃声）
（ケスカス）うわあっ
You're actually kind of cute!
意外とカワイイ
I guess I would have to get
someone better to beat you.
（エリザベス）
さすがに その程度の男じゃ
あなたを倒せないようね
（扉が閉まる音）
（ヴァッシュ）ああ…
What do you mean?
Am I being punished?
どういうことですか？
お仕置きですか？
I want you to die.
（エリザベス）
あなたに死んでほしいのよ
Are you after the reward?
賞金が欲しいんですか？
（エリザベス）違うわ
No.
I want you to die for
0104 A.F., July 21 st, 2:06 am.
理由は 西暦0104年
７月21日 ２時６分
Do you remember?
覚えてる？
That was when you first
got a criminal record.
あなたが初めて
犯罪歴に名を記した時刻
That's right... You transformed
the third city, July, my hometown...
そう… あなたは私の故郷
第３都市ジュライを—
...into Hell!
地獄に変えたのよ
（エリザベス）
フッ あなたが どんな魔法を
使ったか知らないけど—
I don't know what kind
of witchcraft you used...
The city was so badly destroyed,
yet no one was killed.
都市があれだけ破壊されたのに
死者はいなかったわ
But do you know what?
でもね
140万の人が路頭に迷ったのよ
1,400,000 people became
homeless and destitute!
Those people,
parched in both body and soul...
心と体が乾ききった人々は—
ののしり合い 奪い合い
憎み合い続けた
...abused one another,
stole from one another...
...and despised one another.
That's right...
Because of you...
そうよ あなたのせいで
私は地獄の中にたたき込まれ—
...I was thrown into Hell,
and I stayed alive!
そして生き続けてきたのよ
（幼いエリザベス）
お母さん お父さん
Mom...
Dad...
What's wrong?
Why aren't you moving?
なんで なんで動かないの？
うう…
（泣き声）
I remember it even now.
（エリザベス）今でも覚えている
Wandering through the wreckage
of what used to be a city...
当時３つだった私は
廃虚と化した都市をさまよい続けた
...at the age of 3.
あっ
うう… うう…
I'll let you have a taste of
the pain and sadness I felt then.
（エリザベス）
あのときの痛みと苦しみを—
あなたにも与えてあげる
Now is the time...
父と母の敵(かたき)を
今こそ晴らさせてもらうわ！
...to avenge
my mother and father!
Die...
死んで… 死んで償いなさい
Die and repent!
Vash the Stampede!!
ヴァッシュ･ザ･スタンピード！
What can I do...
（ヴァッシュ）
どうすればいい… 俺は
...what?
It's no good.
The power levels aren't dropping!
ダメだ 出力が落ちない
If we don't control it, in a few
hours it will trigger an overflow!
このまま暴走を続ければ
数時間でオーバーフローを起こすぞ
Fire has entered
the Enomes range.
火が入っているのはエノメス級だ
If it explodes, it'll leave
a crater 200 yarz wide!
爆発すれば
200ヤーズの大穴が出来ちまう
I input the data.
How are the power levels?
（エリザベス）
データを送ったわ　出力は？
（作業員Ｄ）
ダメです 下がりません
It's no good!
They're not dropping!
Everyone get away from
the facility! Quickly!
全員施設から避難して　早く！
は… はい
Yes, ma'am!
Excuse me,
but where's Mr. Vash?
あのう ヴァッシュさんは？
He stayed behind.
（エリザベス）彼は残ったわ
（メリル）え？
He's staying there to the end.
最後まで粘ってみるって
But there's no point
in his staying behind!
あの人が残っても意味がなくってよ
- I'm going to get him back!
- But it's no good, ma'am!
連れ戻してきますわ
ダメですってば 先輩
Get out quickly
or you'll be killed.
（エリザベス）
急いで！ 巻き込まれるわよ
うっ 何だ？ プラントが…
What?! The plant is activated.
クソッ あの女
俺まで置き去りにしやがったのか
Damn! Did that woman
leave me to die with him?!
聞いてねえぞ！
That wasn't our deal!
うん？ 何だ？
What?
な… 何なんだ？ あんた…
What the heck are you?
何してんだよ！
What are you doing?!
（人々のざわめき）
This can't be happening!
なんということだ
It was so hard
to get the funds...
せっかく資金も手に入ったのに
We have to run now.
逃げるよ
But Vash is still in there!
でも ヴァッシュが…
Ma'am, come on...
先輩 早く…
（メリル）あっ
（ミリィ）あっ？
The plant!
（メリル）プラントが…
なぜ？
How?!
- The levels are dropping!
- But how did that happen?
（作業員Ｅ）出力が落ちてる
（作業員Ｆ）何だよ？ 理由は
- How should I know?
（作業員Ｇ）そんなの分かるか
It can't be!
（ミリィ）まさか
（メリル）まさか…
It couldn't be!
（扉が開く音）
（ミリィ）あっ
ああ…
（人々の歓声）
（２人）
やった やった やりい！
All right!
やった！ ヴァッシュがやった
He did it! Vash did it!!
信じられませんよ 先輩
I don't believe it, ma'am!
He stopped the plant
from blowing up!!
プラントの暴走を止めちゃいました
えっ ええ…
Yeah.
（市民たち）
ありがとう ヴァッシュ
ありがとう！
Thanks, Mr. Vash!
あ…
Aren't you going?
（ミリィ）行かないんですか？
（メリル）えっ？
He really does like
to scare people.
ホント 人騒がせな人ですわね
Come on, let's go
organize our papers.
さあ 書類整理を始めますわよ
Huh?
（ミリィ）えっ？ はーい 先輩
Ma'am, wait up!
待ってくださいよ
You...
（エリザベス）
あなた どうやって…
How?!
ごめんな 死ななくて
I'm sorry I didn't die.
I didn't want
the city to go with me.
どうしても
町を巻き込みたくなかった
How dare you...
How dare you say that!
よくも… よくも
そんなことが言えるわね！
If you destroyed the plant,
you'd be the same as me.
（ヴァッシュ）
プラントを破壊したら
君は俺と同じになる
I know that...
分かってる
でも あなたに言われたくないわ
...but I don't want
to hear that from you.
ジュライを破壊した あなたに…
You, who destroyed July!
I have no memory.
記憶がないんだ
えっ？
That ruined city
and piles of debris...
（ヴァッシュ）あのとき
荒廃した都市とがれきの山が—
...were the first things
I ever saw.
俺が見た最初の風景だった
I have no memory
of anything before that...
俺には その前の記憶がない
...except for memories
of my childhood.
ずっと前の幼い記憶しか
It wasn't you?
あなたじゃないの？
I don't know.
分からない
Then...
だったら… だったら
あなたを恨ませて！
Then let me blame you for it!
Let me have my revenge!
恨みを晴らさせて！
Way to go, Mr. Vash!
The city is saved!
（男性Ａ）さすがヴァッシュさんだ
（男性Ｂ）これで町も救われたぞ
うう…
Why did it have to be you?!
なんで あなたなの？
Why did someone like you
have to be Vash the Stampede?!
なんで あなたのような人が
ヴァッシュ･ザ･スタンピードなの？
うう…
I'm sorry.
ごめんな
あっ
（エリザベス）
まさか あのときの…
It couldn't be the same man...
ああ…
This can't be...
こんなことって…
It was you?
あなただなんて…
That can't be...
そんなの そんなの…
（エリザベスの泣き声）
♪〜
〜♪
（ヴァッシュ）欲求を満たすために
際限なく繰り返される悲劇
There is a tragedy being
endlessly repeated to fulfil a desire.
征服欲
The lust for conquest. The thrill
of making people bend to your will...
他人を屈服させて
身震いするほどに得られる快感
...is intense enough
to make you shudder.
その恍惚(こうこつ)に身を委ねた男がいる
There is a man who is
a slave to that ecstasy.
The leader of the Bad Lads,
a man who shines...
バドラド団のヘッド… 光る男
...Brilliant Dynamites Neon.
ブリリアント･ダイナマイツ･ネオン
The moment the huge dynamos mounted on
each of his shoulders begin to spark...
彼の両肩にある
巨大なダイナモが光を放つとき—
...the sand steamer will shake.
サンドスチームが震撼(しんかん)する
In the pitch black darkness,
the gruesome party begins.
漆黒の闇の中で
凄惨(せいさん)なる宴(うたげ)が始まる